# Manuel Alejandro Yañez Quintero

Software Engineer

E-mail:

ing.manuel.yanez@gmail.com

Phone:

+57 315 562 4448

## Career Summary

Software Engineer with +8 years of experience in the IT industry involved throughout the software development life cycle (the planning phase, prototyping, data modeling, implementation, testing and maintenance) of web applications, participating in tasks related to collecting requirements from several stakeholders such as customers, internal and external experts, and managers to create a software requirement specification document, validating the solutions and implementing them by using Agile methodologies such as SCRUM, taking advantage of the SCRUM Master Certification completed in 2018.

# Career History

#### Solvo SAS

February 2022– Still

#### Full Stack Developer ( .NET Core, Angular, Vuejs)

Implementing new features and applying improvements on existing systems through APIs and participating in design and coding for User Interfaces for various web-based Professional Employer Organization software.

Leading by example is being my motto in this development team where the transfer of knowledge is a challenge on a daily basis, expending time to mentor new team members, talking to all the team members to provide and receive technical details and participating in the conversations to identify the root cause and technical solutions when the gl reporting team (external from the development team) inform about unexpected behaviors reported by the final users.

### **Globant, Sistemas de Colombia SAS**

May 2021 – February 2022

## .NET Developer

Coding software requirement required to accomplish APIs and Integrations needed on a Financial Web based system, exposing the final core system through secured apis for internal and external applications. The challenge in this development team was to acquire the technical expertise to keep a conversation with senior software developers, and overcome time restrictions for them to share their knowledge, by using the agile mentality on a daily basis communication where every task was the opportunity to collect the puzzle pieces from the business logic and about software architecture.

## **CTI Consulting Bogotá, Colombia**

July 2020 – April 2021

## Web Software Developer & Scrum Master (Net core, kotlin, angular 2+)

Implement development required to accomplish technical plans for maintaining multiple products based on projects assigned.

I was delegated by the team leader in some project to coordinate the agile process with the development team members to apply SCRUM guidelines in the development life cycle.

## **Blackboard Bogotá, Colombia**

Feb. 2019 – June 2020

### Web Software Developer (Angularis, reactis)

Participate in requirement analysis to elaborate technical plans, code to accomplish technical plans for maintaining Ultra Experience core product, contribute actively to writing unit tests, e2e tests to guarantee the expected behavior on every single development.

The scrum methodology in here was used in a consistent way in regards with planning capacities for the team members in the execution of the tasks, and by using the retrospective and review meetings for talking and proving the team member ideas to look for efficiency when understanding the requirements and coding.

### **AOS Bogotá, Colombia**

July 2018 – January 2019

#### Web Software Developer

Review and specify architectural diagrams for maintaining web applications

Handle communications with scrum development team as a member to ensure a proper requirement analysis. Develop web applications to generate customized reports.

## PEVAAR SOFTWARE FACTORY, Bogotá, Colombia

July 2017 – July 2018

## Web Software Developer

Handle communications with English speakers clients to ensure a proper requirement analysis for non english speakers development team. Daily self-study discipline focused on core technologies applied to web development.

Collaborative workflow actively participating with development teams based on assigned projects.

#### **UNIVERSIDAD SERGIO ARBOLEDA**

February 2017 – July 2017

#### **Administrative Assistant**

Customer Service in the Philosophy program handling student issues within academic processes, such as grades, enrollments, graduation documentation, alumni concerns, using SAP ERP and Microsoft Office suite.

#### SITEL COLOMBIA S.A

June 2016 – January 2017

## Technical Support Supervisor (Tier I)

Handle escalated calls for bilingual support over the phone. Following up on complex technical issues for guaranteeing the closing for open cases due to appointment scheduling issues, and repetitive calls from unsolved situations.

## Technical Support Agent (Tier I)

June 2015 – June 2016

Handle bilingual (english and spanish) final users over the phone to walk them through the installation process acquired by mail, adjustments on misconfigurations for TV set top boxes, cable modems for cable, internet and VoIp phone services.

#### Supported devices:

Wifi routers y Cable modems 3.0 DOCSIS from CISCO, Arris/Motorola, Technicolor STB y DVR de CISCO, Motorola, Scientific Atlanta.

# Summary of Qualifications

Core Skills Hard Skills

- Active Listening
- Critical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Teamwork
- Leadership

- Agile Methodologies
- Test Driven Design
- Design Patterns
- .NET ecosystem

#### Web Development Technologies

- ASP.Net MVCWeb API
- Angular JSJquery
- Angular 2+Reactjs

## Databases, related tools and technologies:

- MS SQL Server
- MySQL

MongoDB

## Development methodologies, related tools and technologies:

SCRUM

GIT

UML

# Languages

- Spanish (Native speaker)
- English (C1)

# Experience

• Full Stack .NET Software Developer, Certified Scrum Master, Technical Support Supervisor.

# Education

Solvo University, Colombia

July 2023

Upper Intermediate II English Class

Solvo University, Colombia

April 2023

Upper Intermediate I English Class

CertMind, CCTI, Bogotá, Colombia

August 2018

Scrum Master

Universidad Distrital Francisco José de Caldas, Bogotá, Colombia

July 2017 - July 2018

Software Engineering Specialist

**Universidad de San Buenaventura**, Bogotá, Colombia Bachelor of Science in Sound Engineering

Jan. 2011 - Jul. 2016